Register of the Atlantic Council of the United States Records, 1950-1986
Hoover Institution Archives
- ATLANTIC TREATY ASSOCIATION, 1965-1983
  - Council meetings
    - 1962 June 2-6 (Folder 14)
    - 1963 June 4-6 (Folder 15)
    - 1964
      - February 6-7 (Folder 16)
      - June 18-20 (350, Folder 1-2)
    - 1965
      - June 3-4 (Folder 3)
      - June 9-12 (Folder 4)
    - 1966
      - February 9-11 (Folder 5)
      - July 1-4 (Folder 6)
      - September 18 (Folder 7)
    - 1967
      - January 19-21 (Folder 8)
      - May 24-26 (Folder 9)
    - 1968
      - January 4-5 (351, Folder 1)
      - April 26-27 (Folder 2-3)
    - 1969
      - January 13-14 (Folder 4)
      - May 16-17 (Folder 5)
      - October 19 (Folder 6)
    - 1971 (Folder 7)
    - 1972
      - January 20-21 (Folder 8)
      - April 28-May 3 (Folder 9)
      - June 24-27 (Folder 10)
    - 1973 January 18-19 (Folder 11)
    - 1974 January 18-19 (352, Folder 1)
    - (Brussels), 1975 January 14-18 (Folder 2)
    - 1976 February 22-23 (Folder 3)
    - 1979 January 29-30 (Folder 4)
  - Decolonization Conference, Paris, September 3-8, 1962 (Folder 5)
  - Delegation visit, September 1964 (Folder 6)
  - De Madre, Jean (Folder 7)
  - Education Committee, Ford Foundation, 1966-67 (Folder 8)
  - Educational Secretariat (Folder 9)
  - Educational survey, March 1978 (Folder 10)
  - Eppstein, John (Folder 11)
  - Expenses, 1969 (Folder 12)
  - Financial statement, 1968 (Folder 13)
  - First International Regional Seminar, Kiel, August 5-13, 1961 (Folder 14)
  - Fourth Atlantic Study Conference on Education, July 1962 (Folder 15)
  - General Assemblies
    - 8th, September 23-28, 1962 (Folder 16)
    - 8th, September 23-28, 1962 (353, Folder 1)
    - 9th, (Ankara), September 9-14, 1963 (Folder 2-4)
    - 10th, September 14-19, 1964 (Folder 5-6)
    - 10th, September 14-19, 1964 (354, Folder 1)
    - 11th, September 27-October 1, 1965 (Folder 2-3)
    - 12th, May 24-27, 1966 (Folder 4-7)
    - 13th, September 11-15, 1967
      - General (Folder 8)
      - General (355, Folder 1-4)
      - Delegates (Folder 5)
      - Hotel information (Folder 6)
      - Wallace, Richard J. (Folder 7)
    - 14th, (Lisbon), October 13-18, 1968
      - General (Folder 8-10)
      - Portugese Committee (356, Folder 1)
      - Resolutions and post-Assembly correspondence (Folder 2)
      - U.S. Delegation
        - General (Folder 3)
        - Correspondence (Folder 4)
        - Wallace, Richard (Folder 4A)
    - 15th, October 19-24, 1969
      - General (Folder 5-7)
      - General (357, Folder 1-6)
      - Delegations
        - General (Folder 6A)
        - Belgian (Folder 7)
        - Canadian (Folder 8)
        - Danish (Folder 9)
        - French (Folder 10)
        - German (358, Folder 1)
        - Greek (Folder 2)
        - Icelandic (Folder 3)
        - Italian (Folder 4)
        - Luxembourg (Folder 5)
        - Maltese (Folder 6)
        - Netherlands (Folder 7)
        - Norwegian (Folder 8)
        - Portugese (Folder 9)
      - Hotels (Folder 10-11)
      - Mahias, Pierre (Folder 12)
      - NATO ambassadors (Folder 13)
      - Post-conference (Folder 14)
      - Press releases (Folder 15)
      - Rogers, William P. (Folder 16)
      - SCALANT (Folder 17)
      - Special Panel (Folder 18)
      - Turkey (Folder 19)
      - United Kingdom (Folder 20)
      - U.S. delegates (Folder 21)
      - U.S. delegation luncheon (Folder 22)
      - U.S. observers (Folder 23)
      - Williamsburg (Folder 24)
      - Young Leaders (Folder 25)
    - 16th, (The Hague), September 21-25, 1970 (359, Folder 1-2)
    - 17th, September 20-24, 1971 (Folder 3-6)
    - 18th, September 10-15, 1972 (Folder 7)
    - 18th, September 10-15, 1972 (360, Folder 1)
    - 19th, September 9-14, 1973
      - General (Folder 2)
      - Delegates (Folder 3)
      - Hotel accommodations (Folder 4)
    - 20th, September 9-13, 1974
      - General (Folder 5)
      - Burgess speech (Folder 6)
      - Committee assignments (Folder 7)
      - Delegate appointment letters (Folder 8)
      - Papers (Folder 9)
      - Program (Folder 10)
      - Reports (Folder 11)
    - 21st, October 20-24, 1975 (Folder 12)
    - 21st, October 20-24, 1975 (361, Folder 1)
    - 22nd, (Copenhagen), September 3-6, 1976 (Folder 2)
  - Grant request, 1976 (Folder 3)
  - Greenwich seminar, June 25-27, 1975 (Folder 4)
  - Hamburg Conference, September 1978 (Folder 5-6)
  - Iceland, July 1976 (Folder 7)
  - Information Committee (362, Folder 1)
  - Interim Report, May 1975 (Folder 2)
  - ISMIR Seminar, May 20-21, 1977 (Folder 3)
  - Lisbon Seminar, May 1978 (Folder 4)
  - London Congress, 1971 (Folder 5)
  - Mahias, Pierre (Folder 6)
  - Meetings
    - 1964 June 14-17 (Folder 7)
    - 1974 June 19-22 (Folder 8)
  - Moynihan, Daniel P. (Folder 9)
  - Naples Mediterranean Seminar, March 1970 (Folder 10)
  - The Netherlands, 1970 (Folder 11)
  - Norfolk Seminar, May 24-26, 1973 (Folder 12)
  - Polmar, Norman, "Outflanking NATO?", 1976 (Folder 13)
  - Presidency, 1979 (Folder 14)
  - Press conference lunch, March 15, 1966 (Folder 15)
  - Printed matter (363, Folder 1)
  - Programs
    - 1963 (Folder 2)
    - 1964 (Folder 3)
  - Programs abroad
    - 1968 (Folder 4)
    - 1969 (Folder 5)
  - Questionnaire, 1977 (Folder 6)
  - Reception, September 24-25, 1964 (Folder 7)
  - Report to, 1973-74 (Folder 8)
  - Rogers, William P. (Folder 9)
  - Rostow, Eugene V. (Folder 10)
  - Seminar, Norfolk, May 1973 (Folder 11)
  - Thank-you letters (Folder 12)
  - Translators (Folder 13)
  - Wilcox, Francis O. (Folder 14)
  - Young Leader participation in the ATA General Assembly (Folder 15)
  - Young Leaders
    - American (Folder 16)
    - Belgian (Folder 17)
    - British (Folder 18)
    - Canadian (Folder 19)
    - Danish (Folder 20)
    - French (Folder 21)
    - German (Folder 22)
    - Greek (Folder 23)
    - Icelandic (Folder 24)
    - Italian (Folder 25)
    - Luxembourg (Folder 26)
    - Maltese (Folder 27)
    - Netherlands (Folder 28)
    - Norwegian (Folder 29)
    - Portugese (Folder 30)
    - Turkish (Folder 31)
  - Young Leaders Caucus (Folder 32)
  - Youth Conference, Port Cros, July 11-25, 1962 (364, Folder 1)
- COMMITTEE ON ATLANTIC STUDIES, 1964-1972
  - 1964 (364, Folder 2)
  - 1964-66 (Folder 3)
  - 1966-67 (Folder 4)
  - 1969 (Folder 5-6)
  - 1969-1970 (Folder 7)
  - 1971 (Folder 8-9)
  - 1971-72 (Folder 10)
  - General (Folder 11)
  - Acceptance letters (Folder 12)
  - Canada seminar, September 1968 (365, Folder 1)
  - Combined CAS (European & American) agreement and executive body correspondence (Folder 2)
  - Conferences
    - 1965 October 8-9 (Folder 3)
    - 1968 September 9-13 (Folder 4)
    - 1972 April 14-16 (Folder 5)
  - Correspondence
    - 1963-65 (Folder 6)
    - 1966
      - January (Folder 7)
      - February-March (Folder 8)
      - April-May (Folder 9)
      - June-July (Folder 10)
      - August-December (Folder 11)
      - October (Folder 12)
    - 1967
      - January-March (Folder 13)
      - April-June (366, Folder 1)
      - July-September (Folder 2)
      - October-December (Folder 3)
    - 1968
      - January-April (Folder 4)
      - January-July (Folder 5)
      - September-December (Folder 6)
    - 1969
      - July-December (Folder 7)
      - September-December (Folder 8)
    - 1970 Summer (Folder 9)
    - 1971 February-June (Folder 10)
    - English, H. E., 1967 (Folder 11)
    - Feld, Werner, 1967 (367, Folder 1)
    - Kitzengers, 1968-69 (Folder 2)
    - Lawson, Ruth, 1968 (Folder 3)
    - Mosely, Philip, 1967 (Folder 4)
    - Pick, Otto, 1970-72 (Folder 5)
    - Strausz-Hupe, Robert, 1967 (Folder 6)
    - Telders, Charles, 1968 (Folder 7)
    - Tuthill, John W., 1970 (Folder 8)
    - Warfield, Benjamin B., 1964-68 (Folder 9)
    - Wolfers, Arnold, 1964 (Folder 10)
  - Dowling, Walter C. (Folder 11)
  - Duroselle, J. B., "The Future of the Atlantic Community,", September 1966 (Folder 12)
  - Exchange program resolution (Folder 13)
  - Grant requests (Folder 14)
  - Graz Center (Folder 15)
  - Jordan, Robert S., "An Analysis of the State of European and Atlantic Relations,", February 26, 1970 (Folder 16)
  - Kitzinger, Uwe (Folder 17)
  - Lipson, Leslie
    - Correspondence, 1967-1970 (Folder 18)
    - Report on discussion of paper presented by Waldemar Besson at Villa Serbelloni Conference (Folder 19)
  - List of possible European nominees for Atlantic Colloquium, 1966 (Folder 20)
  - Luza, Radomir (Folder 21)
  - Meetings
    - 1964
      - February 22 (Folder 22)
      - October 3 (Folder 23)
    - 1965
      - February 13 (Folder 24)
      - September 9 (Folder 25)
      - September 11 (Folder 26)
    - 1966
      - January 15 (368, Folder 1)
      - March 12 (Folder 2)
      - October 29 (Folder 3-5)
    - 1967
      - April 8 (Folder 6)
      - October 28 (Folder 7)
    - 1968
      - April 20 (Folder 8)
      - (Quebec), September 12 (369, Folder 1-2)
    - 1969
      - February 15 (Folder 3)
      - March 17 (Folder 4)
      - July (Folder 5)
    - 1970
      - February 28 (Folder 6)
      - Fall (Folder 7)
      - Various dates (Folder 8)
    - 1971 February 13 (Folder 9)
    - Press coverage (Folder 10)
  - Members
    - Biographies (Folder 11)
    - Brooks, E. Howard (Folder 12)
    - Cole, R. Taylor (Folder 13)
    - Deutsch, Harold C. (Folder 14)
    - English, H. Edward (370, Folder 1)
    - Feld, Werner (Folder 2)
    - Flynt, Ralph (Folder 3)
    - Frank, Isaiah (Folder 4)
    - Geiger, Theodore (Folder 5)
    - Hanna, Paul R. (Folder 6)
    - Jordan, Robert S. (Folder 7)
    - Kohn, Hans (Folder 8)
    - Korbel, Josef (Folder 9)
    - Lawson, Ruth C. (Folder 10)
    - Lipson, Leslie (Folder 11)
    - Mosely, Philip E. (Folder 12)
    - Munk, Frank (Folder 13)
    - Painchaud, Paul (Folder 14)
    - Spencer, Robert A. (Folder 15)
    - Stein, Eric (Folder 16)
    - Tuthill, John W. (Folder 17)
    - Von Geusau, Alting (Folder 18)
    - New members (Folder 19)
  - NATO anniversary, 1969 (371, Folder 1)
  - Office supplies and procedures (Folder 2)
  - Papers and reports, 1967-68 (Folder 3)
  - Program summary, 1965 (Folder 4)
  - Questionnaire, 1971 (Folder 5)
  - Resolution, 1969 (Folder 6)
  - Resolution for a grant in support of a program in Atlantic and Western European studies, September 25, 1964 (Folder 7)
  - Revised agenda, April 11, 1969 (Folder 8)
  - Rostow, Eugene V., "Possible Futures for the Atlantic Community: A Comment on Professor J. D. Duroselle's Paper," draft B, n.d. (Folder 9)
  - Seminars
    - 1969 (Folder 10)
    - University of Missouri, April 3-4, 1969
      - General (Folder 11)
      - Edinger, Lewis, "The German Republic and NATO: Problems and Prospects" (Folder 12)
  - Spring meeting, April 1968 (Folder 13)
  - Subcommittee for Regional Studies (Werner Feld) (Folder 14)
  - Subcommittee on Graduate Study Abroad
    - Atlantic studies in the U.S., draft report, 1965 (Folder 15)
    - Background note on Recommendations, 3 and 4, 2/14/66 (Folder 16)
    - Meetings
      - 1966
        - January 15 (Folder 17)
        - March 12 (372, Folder 1)
        - October 29 (Folder 2)
      - 1967 April 8 (Folder 3)
  - Subcommittee on Visiting Atlantic Studies, meetings
    - 1966 October 29 (Folder 4)
    - 1967 April 8 (Folder 5)
  - Trans-Atlantic Colloquium, Royaumont, July 7-10, 1966 (Folder 6-8)
  - Trans-Atlantic Conference, March 12, 1966 (Folder 9)
  - Travel expense forms (Folder 10)
  - Villa Serbelloni Conference, September 12-16, 1967 (Folder 11-12)
  - Visiting scholars (373, Folder 1)
  - Von Geusau, Alting (Folder 2)
  - Working outline for a bibliography on Atlantic studies (Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 4)
- PHONORECORDS
  - #1-2) Sound recording of "Robert St. John Reports: General Media Associates, Chicago, IL, Week of January 25-29, 1965
  - #3) Sound recording of "Bob Hope Speaks Up for NATO" for the NATO campaign, 1969
    This 1969 NATO campaign was sponsored by the Atlantic Council of the United States. Messages included are (1) "Playground," (2) "Factory," (3) "Playground," (4) "Factory," and (5) NATO I.D. These messages are supported by the Advertising Council and listed in its media bulletins. Volunteer agency: J. Walter Thompson Company
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Use copy reference number: 82069_a_0003849
- PHONOTAPES
  - #1) Highlights of the Atlantic Congress sound recording, June 5-10, 1959
    This recording was specifically produced for the Broadcasting Foundation of America by BBC, and transmitted by direct cable on June 10. Meeting in London, the Congress, which was organized by the NATO Parliamentarians' conference, discussed the relations between NATO countries and the free and uncommitted world, between NATO countries themselves, and between NATO and the Communist bloc. The meeting was opened by Queen Elizabeth of England; Prince Bernhard of the Netherlands gave the summary and concluding remarks. Excerpts from these and other prominent speakers from Europe and the U.S.A. are linked by narration of Lloyd James. This is a Special Service program of BFA.
    Use copy reference number: 82069_a_0003851
  - #2) "CBS Christmas Promo (NATO)"
  - #3) Robert St. John, various topics
  - 9 phonotapes relating to Atlantic Council events and interviews, 1969 (Increment, July 1990)
    - Sound recording of C.I.I.A. meeting at Maison Montmorency, 12 September 1968
      The chairman is Painchaud and the speakers are Hanna, Painchaud, Huntly, Von Geusau, Munk, Hassner, Andren, Casanova, W. Tr. Fox, Lipson
      Use copy reference number: 82069_a_0003852
    - Sound recording of Atlantic Treaty Association General Assembly meeting, 20-21 October 1969
      Use copy reference number: 82069_a_0003853
- VIDEOTAPES
  - 3 videotapes labelled "NATO: World Fire," (Increment July 1990), 1984-86 (Reel Videotape)
- PHOTOGRAPHS.
  - See photo card catalogue for description. (Folder 10.A-V)
- MICROFILMS
  - 5 microfilm reels containing serial issues of Atlantic Community Quarterly, Atlantic Comminity News, and Asphalt, (Increment July 1990), 1967-1983 (Oversize Microfilm Cabinet)
- MOTION PICTURE FILMS
  - 2 16mm motion picture film reels labelled "NATO: World Fire" (Increment, July 1990 (Shelf Film Shelf)